Fire burns brighter in the darkness.
The Hunger Games: Mockingjay - Part 1 is a science fiction,
adventure, thriller film directed by Francis Lawrence.
After surviving the Quarter Quell, Katniss finds herself in the hidden stronghold of
District 13, where the rebellion against the Capitol is gaining momentum.
Struggling with the weight of becoming the symbol of resistance, she must
navigate fragile alliances while trying to protect those she loves.
As propaganda battles rage and Panem moves closer to full-scale war,
Katniss is forced to confront the true cost of revolution.
Katniss Everdeen, played by Jennifer Lawrence.
Peeta Mellark, played by Josh Hutcherson.
Gale Hawthorne, played by Liam Hemsworth.
Haymitch Abernathy, played by Woody Harrelson.
Effie Trinket, played by Elizabeth Banks.
President Alma Coin, played by Julianne Moore.
The Hunger Games: Mockingjay – Part 2 is a 2015 American dystopian action film directed by Francis Lawrence from a
screenplay by Peter Craig and Danny Strong, based on the 2010 novel Mockingjay by Suzanne Collins.
The sequel to The Hunger Games: Mockingjay – Part 1 (2014), it is the fourth installment in The
Hunger Games film series and the final installment in the original film series.
The film stars Jennifer Lawrence, Josh Hutcherson, Liam Hemsworth, Woody Harrelson, Elizabeth Banks, Julianne Moore,
Jeffrey Wright, Stanley Tucci, Donald Sutherland, and in his final film role, Philip Seymour Hoffman.
In the film, Katniss Everdeen (Lawrence) leads a team of rebels into the very heart of the Capitol to
liberate it and all of Panem from the tyrannical leadership of Coriolanus Snow (Sutherland).
Together with its predecessor, principal photography began in September 2013 and lasted until June 2014, taking
place back-to-back, with filming locations including Boston, Atlanta, Paris, Berlin, and Los Angeles.
Hoffman, who died in February 2014, completed the majority of his
scenes, although his death caused others to be rewritten.
The Hunger Games: Mockingjay – Part 2 premiered at the Sony Center in Berlin on November 4, 2015, and
was released in the United States on November 20, by Lionsgate, in 2D, 3D, and IMAX.
The film received generally positive reviews from critics, with praise for its performances (particularly Lawrence, Hutcherson and Sutherland's), screenplay,
music, and action sequences; it was deemed a fitting end to the series, although some were divided on the decision to split the novel into two films.
It grossed $661.4 million, making it the ninth-highest-grossing film of 2015.
Among its accolades, the film was nominated for Best
Fantasy Film at the 42nd Saturn Awards.
It received three nominations at the 21st Empire Awards for Best Sci-Fi/Fantasy, Best Actress (Lawrence) and Best Production
Design, while Lawrence was nominated for Best Actress in an Action Movie at the 21st Critics' Choice Awards.
A prequel film, The Hunger Games: The Ballad of Songbirds &
Snakes,  was released on November 17, 2023.
The film explores themes of based on novel or book,
resistance, dystopia, post-apocalyptic future, sequel.
The tone is thought_provoking and intense.